Guide to the Council on Southeast Asia Studies, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Council on Southeast Asia Studies, Yale University, records
1942-1973
RU 598
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
26.5
The records consist of correspondence, subject files, student and faculty files, and printed material documenting Professor Harry J. Benda's directorship of the Southeast Asia Studies program at Yale. Also included are files of Karl J. Pelzer, chairman of the Council on Southeast Asia Studies.
Yale University. Southeast Asia Studies
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 3-C (YRG 3-C), Records of Yale academic divisions, councils, and committees.
Conditions Governing Access
While this collection as a whole is available for research, parts of it may be restricted due to law, university policy or fragility. Any restricted material will be noted as such.
Arrangement
The records are arranged in two series: I. Correspondence, 1949-1973. II. Subject Files, 1942-1972; and subsequent accessions.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, subject files, student and faculty files, and printed material documenting Professor Harry J. Benda's directorship of the Southeast Asia Studies program at Yale. Also included are files of Karl J. Pelzer, chairman of the Council on Southeast Asia Studies.
Southeast Asia -- Study and teaching; Benda, Harry Jindrich; Pelzer, Karl J. (Karl Josef), 1909-1980; Yale University. Southeast Asia Studies
- Correspondence, 1949-1973; Series I
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Administrative, 1949-1951 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Administrative, 1952-1957 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Administrative, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Council of Learned Societies, 1959-1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Historical Association, 1957-1960 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Historical Association, 1961-1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Historical Association: Conference on Asian History, 1964-1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1965 Meeting (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1967 Meeting (Toronto) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - American Philosophical Society, 1962-1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Annals, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Asia Foundation, 1957-1961 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Asia Society, 1965-1971 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Asia Society: Indonesian Council, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Asia Society: Indonesian Council, 1968-1970 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Asia Society: Indonesian Council, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Asian Survey, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Association for Asian Studies, 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Association for Asian Studies, 1968-1970 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - International Liaison Committee, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Interuniversity Southeast Asia Committee, Language Resource Subcommittee, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Southeast Asia Committee, 1960-1964 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Australian National University, 1968-1970 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Australia, miscellaneous, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - A General, 1962-1971 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - B General, 1960-1966 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - B General, 1967-1971 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - California, University of, at Berkeley, 1965-1967 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - California, University of, at Santa Barbara, 1966-1968 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Center for Advanced Study (Stanford), 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Choice, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Cornell Southeast Asia Program (SEW), 1963 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Council for a Livable World, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, Inc., 1965-1968 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - C General, 1960-1971 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Daedalus, 1968-1971 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - D General, 1960-1971 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - East-West Center, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Eckstein, Alexander, 1958-1969 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Educational Television, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Encyclopedia of Islam, 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Evers, Hans-Dieter, Director of Graduate Studies, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - E General, 1960-1969 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Faruqi, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Ford Foundation, 1959-1971 (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - Ford Foundation (Kuala Lumpur), 1969 (Box 5, Folder 78)
  - Foreign Area Fellowship Program, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 79)
  - Foreign Service Institute, 1967-1970 (Box 5, Folder 80)
  - Freie Universitat Berlin (Free University of Berlin), 1964 (Box 5, Folder 83)
  - Fulbright, 1960-1966 (Box 5, Folder 85)
  - F General, 1961-1970 (Box 5, Folder 87)
  - Galbraith, Ambassador Francis J., 1966-1968 (Box 5, Folder 88)
  - Guggenheim Foundation, 1961-1968 (Box 5, Folder 97)
  - G General, 1963-1970 (Box 5, Folder 99)
  - Hebrew University, Jerusalem, 1961-1971 (Box 6, Folder 102)
  - Kong Kong Conference, 1962-1964 (Box 6, Folder 106)
  - H General, 1963-1970 (Box 6, Folder 109)
  - Indonesian Embassy and Consulate General, 1959-1970 (Box 6, Folder 110)
  - Indonesian Round Table, 1963-1968 (Box 6, Folder 111)
  - Institut fur Asienkunde, Hamburg, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 112)
  - Institute for International Youth Affairs, 1960-1963 (Box 6, Folder 113)
  - Institute for Mediterranean Affairs, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 114)
  - Institute of International Education, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 115)
  - Institute of Southeast Asian Studies, Singapore, 1968 December 20-1969 September 26 (Box 6, Folder 116)
  - Institute of Southeast Asian Studies, Singapore, 1969 October 7-December 26 (Box 6, Folder 117)
  - Institute of Southeast Asian Studies, Singapore, 1970 January 19-March 27 (Box 6, Folder 118)
  - Institute of Southeast Asian Studies, Singapore, 1970 April 7-December 14 (Box 6, Folder 119)
  - Institute of Southeast Asian Studies, Singapore, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 120)
  - International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, 1963-1967 (Box 6, Folder 121)
  - International Congress of Orientalists (27th), 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 122)
  - International Congress of Orientalists (28th), Canberra, 1969-1971 (Box 7, Folder 123)
  - I General, 1961-1971 (Box 7, Folder 127)
  - Journal of Asian Studies, 1965-1971 (Box 7, Folder 138)
  - Journal of Modern History, 1957-58 (Box 7, Folder 139)
  - J General, 1963-1970 (Box 7, Folder 140)
  - Koninklijk Instituut voor Taal-, Land- en Volkenkunde (Royal Institute of Linguistics and Anthropology, Leiden), 1956-1971 (Box 8, Folder 148)
  - Kyoto Southeast Asia Center, 1965-1968 (Box 8, Folder 150)
  - K General, 1961-1970 (Box 8, Folder 151)
  - Library of Congress, 1956-1970 (Box 9, Folder 167)
  - L General, 1963-1971 (Box 9, Folder 172)
  - Malaya, University of, 1962-1970 (Box 10, Folder 181)
  - Malaya, University of, in Kuala Lumpur, 1960-1965 (Box 10, Folder 182)
  - Malaya, University of, in Singapore, 1960-1965 (Box 10, Folder 183)
  - Michigan, University of, Press, 1966-1968 (Box 10, Folder 187)
  - M General, 1958-1971 (Box 10, Folder 191)
  - Northern Illinois Center, 1967-1968 (Box 10, Folder 200)
  - N General, 1962-1972 (Box 10, Folder 201)
  - Office of Education, 1965-1971 (Box 11, Folder 203)
  - Office of Education, Meeting of Field Readers, Intensive Sumer Language Program, 1971 August 10-11 (Box 11, Folder 204)
  - Oregon, University of, 1964-1971 (Box 11, Folder 205)
  - O General, 1961-1970 (Box 11, Folder 208)
  - Pacific Affairs, 1962-1966 (Box 11, Folder 210)
  - Philippines, 1963-1966 (Box 12, Folder 219)
  - P General, 1961-1970 (Box 12, Folder 223)
  - Rand Corporation, 1958-1960 (Box 12, Folder 224)
  - Random House, Inc., 1970 (Box 12, Folder 225)
  - R General, 1961-1967 (Box 12, Folder 234)
  - R General, 1968-1970 (Box 12, Folder 235)
  - Scribner's Publishers, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 241)
  - Social Science Research Council, 1955-1964 (Box 13, Folder 256)
  - Social Science Research Council, Sino-Vietnamese Pact, 1964-1968 (Box 13, Folder 257)
  - Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group (SEADAG), 1965-1970 (Box 13, Folder 259)
  - Spiegel Historiael, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 260)
  - Sydney, University of, 1968-1970 (Box 14, Folder 267)
  - Sydney, University of, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 268)
  - S General, 1959-1968 (Box 14, Folder 269)
  - S General, 1969-1971 (Box 14, Folder 270)
  - The Siauw Giap, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 272)
  - T General, 1962-1970 (Box 14, Folder 279)
  - United States Government, Department of State, 1955-1963 (Box 14, Folder 280)
  - U General, 1964-1967 (Box 14, Folder 282)
  - V General, 1959-1970 (Box 15, Folder 294)
  - W General, 1957-1966 (Box 15, Folder 313)
  - W General, 1967-1971 (Box 15, Folder 314)
  - Y General, 1965-1970 (Box 15, Folder 317)
- Subject files, 1942-1972; Series II
  The materials are open for research, with the exception of materials in boxes 26-28, which is restricted due to University policy until January 1, 2046.
  - Professional Organizations and Conferences
    - American Assembly (See: Asian-American Assembly)
    - American Institute of Pacific Relations (See: pacific Affairs, Institute of pacific Relations)
    - Asia Society, Indonesian Council:
      - minutes of meetings, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 314)
      - minutes of meetings, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 315)
      - minutes of meetings, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 316)
      - correspondence, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 317)
      - correspondence, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 318)
      - correspondence, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 319)
      - minutes of meetings, correspondence, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 320)
    - Asian-American Assembly, University of Malaya:
      - correspondence, 1963 January-1963 Jun, undated (Box 16, Folder 321)
      - pamphlets of Malaya and the University of Malaya, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 322)
    - Association for Asian Studies:
      - Constitution, undated (Box 16, Folder 323)
      - Nominating Committee for Board of Directors, 1963-1964, correspondence, 1962-1964 (Box 16, Folder 324)
      - Program Committee for 1964 correspondence, 1962-1964 (Box 16, Folder 325)
      - Program Committee for 1965 correspondence
        - 1963 Nov-1964 Feb (Box 16, Folder 326)
        - 1964 Mar (Box 16, Folder 327)
        - 1964 Apr (Box 16, Folder 328)
        - 1964 May (Box 16, Folder 329)
        - 1964 Jun (Box 16, Folder 330)
        - 1964 Jul-Aug (Box 16, Folder 331)
        - 1964 Sep (Box 16, Folder 332)
        - 1964 Oct (Box 16, Folder 333)
        - 1964 Nov (Box 17, Folder 334)
        - 1964 Dec (Box 17, Folder 335)
      - Program Committee for 1966 correspondence, 1965 January (Box 17, Folder 336)
      - Program Committee for 1965 correspondence, 1965 February-Apr, undated (Box 17, Folder 337)
      - Program for Sixteenth Annual meeting, 1964 March 20-22 (Box 17, Folder 338)
      - Program for 1966, "Islam in Contemporary Asia," by Harry J. Benda correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 17, Folder 339)
      - Annual Reports, 1967-1968 (Box 17, Folder 340)
    - Association for Asian Studies, Inc.
      - Audit Report, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 341)
    - Association for Asian Studies
      - Annual Report, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 342)
      - Annual Reports, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 343)
      - Board of Directors, 1968-1969 (Box 17, Folder 344)
      - Memoranda to Officers and Directors, 1968-1969 (Box 17, Folder 345)
      - Memoranda to Officers and Directors, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 346)
      - Minutes of meetings of Officers and Board of Directors, 1968-1969 (Box 17, Folder 347)
      - correspondence of the Board of Directors, 1968-1970 (Box 17, Folder 348)
      - Proposal to Ford Foundation from the Interuniversity Southeast Asia Committee, 1968 Sep, 1969 June (Box 17, Folder 349)
      - Interuniversity Southeast Asia Committee
        - Statement of purpose (first and second drafts), undated (Box 17, Folder 350)
        - Untitled statement on Southeast Asia Studies, undated (Box 17, Folder 351)
        - Constitution and by-laws (proposed changes), 1969 May 21 (Box 17, Folder 352)
        - correspondence, minutes of meetings, related papers, 1969 January 15-1969 August 7 (Box 17, Folder 353)
        - correspondence, minutes of meetings, related papers, 1969 September 3-1969 October 24 (Box 17, Folder 354)
        - correspondence, minutes of meetings, related papers, 1969 November 18-1969 December 12 (Box 18, Folder 355)
        - correspondence, minutes of meetings, related papers, 1970-1971, undated (Box 18, Folder 356)
    - International Conference on Asian History, Kuala Lumpur, 1968
      - correspondence, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 357)
      - correspondence, 1968 January-Jun, undated (Box 18, Folder 358)
      - papers presented on Asian History:
        - Anon, "The Revolt of a Peta Battalion in Blitar, February 14, 1945" (Box 18, Folder 359)
        - Yoji Akashd, "Japanese Military Administration in Malaya, Its Formation and Evolution in Reference to Sultans, the Islamic Religion, and the Moslem Malays, 1941-1945" (Box 18)
        - Milagros C. Guerrero, "Japanese Propaganda in the Philippines, 1942-1945" (Box 18)
        - Joyce C. Lebra, "Japanese Policy and the Indian National Army" (Box 18)
        - Shinjiro Nagaoki, "Some Government Decisions on Japan's Southward Advance" (Box 18)
    - International Journal,canadian Institute of International Affairs
      - correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 18, Folder 360)
    - Pacific Affairs, American Institute of Pacific Relations
      - annual reports, 1956 June, 1958 June 30 (Box 18, Folder 361)
    - Pacific Affairs, Institute of Pacific Relations
      - correspondence, 1955-1959 (Box 18, Folder 362)
      - correspondence, 1960-1967 (Box 18, Folder 363)
    - Royal Institute for Linguistics and Anthropology at Leiden
      - correspondence, 1967 December-1968 April (Box 18, Folder 364)
    - U.S. Dept. of State, Foreign Service Institute
      - correspondence, 1961-1964 May (Box 18, Folder 365)
      - correspondence, 1964 July-1966 (Box 18, Folder 366)
    - U.S. Dept. of State, Foreign Service Institute, Senior Seminar in Foreign Policy, 1971 August 16-1972 June 9 (Box 18, Folder 367)
  - Writings and Lectures
    - Papers on Islam in Southeast Asia:
      - Anon., "Abstract: The Mores of the Philippines" (Box 18, Folder 368)
      - Robert B. Fox, "A Consideration of Theories Concerning Possible Affiliations of Mlndinao Cultures with Borneo, the Celebes, and other Regions of the Philippines" (Box 18)
      - Melvin Mednick, "Some problems of Moro Hifttory and Political Organization" (Box 18)
      - John Leddy phelan, "Spanish Penetration into the Southern Philippines (1578-1662)", undated (Box 18)
      - Paul Lietz, "Mindanao in the Nineteenth Century", undated (Box 18)
      - Anon., "The Moros in the Context of the Philippines", undated (Box 18, Folder 369)
      - Anon., "The Moros", undated (Box 18)
      - Anon., "The Muslim Minority in the Philippines", 1962 June 11 (Box 18)
      - Felix M. Keesing, "Mindanao: Future Perspectives", undated (Box 18)
      - Frederick L. Wernstedt, "Geographic Foundations of Mindanao", undated (Box 18)
      - Chester L. Hunt, "Ethnic Stratification and Integration in Cotabato", undated (Box 18)
      - Mohamed H. Faki, "Moslem Pilgrims to Saudi Arabia", 1964 (Box 19, Folder 370)
      - Seato Press Release, "Islam: a Flourishing Faith in Thailand", undated (Box 19)
      - Anon., "De Wijen Van Verbreiding", undated (Box 19)
      - Anon., "Belangstelling voor Het Centrumvan De Islam", undated (Box 19, Folder 371)
      - Anon., "The Malays of South Thailand", undated (Box 19)
      - L. Shap (ed.), Thailand, excerpt, 1956 (Box 19)
      - Anon., "Islamic Groups in Cambodia and South Vietnam", post-1959 (Box 19)
      - F. Suffian Hashim, "The Relationship Between Islam and the State of Malaya", undated (Box 19)
    - Papers on Peasant Movements in Southeast Asia:
      - William H. Frederick, "The Sakdal Revolt of May 2-3, 1935", 1963 May (Box 19, Folder 372)
      - Harry J. Benda, "Peasant Movements in Colonial Southeast Asia", undated (Box 19)
      - Excerpts from other works on peasant movements, undated (Box 19)
    - Papers on Western Intellectuals: Anon., undated (Box 19, Folder 373)
    - Anon., "Some Comments on the Single Tax Movement in New Zealand", 1954 January (Box 19, Folder 374)
    - Harry J. Benda, "The Closing Years of Dutch Rule in Indonesia", 1953 (Box 19, Folder 375)
    - Harry J. Benda, "Reflections on Asian Conununism," long and short versions for the Yale Review, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 376)
    - Harry J. Benda, "Rousseau's Early Discourses," fragment, undated (Box 19, Folder 377)
    - "Asia and Democracy," fragment, undated (Box 19, Folder 378)
    - Hajji Yusut Chang, "Islam in Modern China", -1966 (Box 19, Folder 379)
    - Book reviews by Harry J. Benda, 1955-1970 (Box 19, Folder 380)
    - Review of book by Harry J. Benda, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 381)
    - Public lecture notes, undated (Box 19, Folder 382)
    - Research notes on Indonesia; excerpts from printed works, undated (Box 19, Folder 383)
    - Speech given on "Yale Reports," WTIC, Hartford, CT. by Harry J. Benda, 1965 May 30 (Box 19, Folder 384)
    - Yale student papers, notes, History 271, 1965-1966 (Box 19, Folder 385)
    - Subject bibliographies, Southeast Asia, 1954-1958 (Box 19, Folder 386)
    - Syllabi and lecture notes for classes given at Cornell by Harry J. Benda, 1952-1959 (Box 19, Folder 387)
    - Syllabi and notes, Yale University, History 72b, Modern History and Southeast Asia, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 388)
    - A Study of Japanese Military Administration in Indonesia:
      - Okuma Memorial Social Science Research Institute, Waseda University, by Nishijima Shitegada and Kishi Koichi, outline of contents, typescript, undated (Box 20, Folder 389)
      - Preface, typescript, Table of Contents, typescript and carbon copy, undated (Box 20, Folder 390)
      - Chapter I, Introduction, typescript, undated (Box 20, Folder 391)
      - Chapter II, Section 1, typescript with corrections, undated (Box 20, Folder 392)
      - Chapter IV, Sections 1 and 2, typescript with corrections, undated (Box 20, Folder 393)
      - Chapter IV, Sections 3 and 4, with corrections, undated (Box 20, Folder 394)
      - Chapter IV, Sections 5, typescript with corrections, undated (Box 20, Folder 395)
      - Chapter IV, Sections 3, 4, 5, typescript, undated (Box 20, Folder 396)
      - Chapter IV, Section 6, typescript with corrections, undated (Box 20, Folder 397)
      - Chapter IV, Section 3 onwards, typescript, undated (Box 20, Folder 398)
      - Chapter V, Section 1, typescript with corrections, undated (Box 20, Folder 399)
      - Chapter V, Section 1, typescript, undated (Box 20, Folder 400)
      - Chapter VI, fragment of Section 1 and Section 2, typescript, undated (Box 20, Folder 401)
      - Chapter VI, Section 1 and 2, typescript, undated (Box 20, Folder 402)
      - Chapter VII, postscript, typescript, undated (Box 20, Folder 403)
      - Chapter VII, undated (Box 20, Folder 404)
      - Fragment of chapter VII and conclusion, typescript with corrections, undated (Box 21, Folder 405)
      - Conclusion and postscript, typescript, undated (Box 21, Folder 406)
      - Appendix, carbon copy; Table of Contents forAppendix typescript with corrections, pencil, undated (Box 21, Folder 407)
      - Bibliography, typescript with corrections, two typescripts, undated (Box 21, Folder 408)
      - unidentified Japanese document, 1958 (Box 21, Folder 409)
    - List of Japanese documents for a study of the impact of Japanese military government on the Indonesian Independence, typescript, carbon, and 2 copies, undated (Box 21, Folder 410)
    - A Study of Japanese Military Administration in Indonesia:
      - corrections for the manuscript by Irikura, typescripts, undated (Box 21, Folder 411)
      - notes, on translation, Japanese to Dutch, Japanese to English, undated (Box 21, Folder 412)
    - Decree from the Japanese Military Commander (Dutch trans.), 1942 March 28 (Box 21, Folder 413)
    - Publication file correspondence, 1959-1966 (Box 21, Folder 414)
    - Grant and Fellowship Brochures
      - ABT Associates, Inc., 1965 (Box 22, Folder 415)
      - American Council of Learned Societies, Foreign Area Training Fellowships, 1962-1967 (Box 22, Folder 416)
      - Conference Board of Associated Research Councils, Committee on the International Exchange of Persons, under Fulbright-Hays Act, 1961-1967, undated (Box 22, Folder 417)
      - Experiment in International Living, 1964, undated (Box 22, Folder 418)
      - Ford Foundation, 1952-1962 (Box 22, Folder 419)
      - Institute of International Education, 1961-1967, undated (Box 22, Folder 420)
      - International Voluntary Services, 1964-1965, undated (Box 22, Folder 421)
      - Michigan, University of, Center for South and Southeast Asian Studies, Vietnam Fellowship, undated (Box 22, Folder 422)
      - National Defense Modern Foreign Language Awards Undergraduate Pilot Project, 1962-1963 (Box 22, Folder 423)
      - National Academy of Sciences, National Research Council, 1965 (Box 22, Folder 424)
      - National Security Agency, 1962-1964 (Box 22, Folder 425)
      - Overseas Educational Service, post-1963 (Box 22, Folder 426)
      - Pennsylvania, University of, American Institute of Indian Studies, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 427)
      - Social Science Research Council, 1965-1966 (Box 22, Folder 428)
      - Wisconsin, University of, International Studies and Programs, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 429)
      - United States Civil Service Commission, 1961 (Box 22, Folder 430)
      - United States Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, Office of Education, 1961-1965 (Box 22, Folder 431)
      - United States Department of State, 1961-1965 (Box 22, Folder 432)
      - United States Information Agency, 1961-1963, undated (Box 22, Folder 433)
      - United States Information Agency, Voice of America, 1962-1963 (Box 22, Folder 434)
      - United States National Commission for UNESCO, 1965 (Box 22, Folder 435)
    - Departmental Files
      - Yale University Southeast Asia Study Center annual plans of operation and technical reports, 1962-1969 (Box 23, Folder 436)
      - Yale University, Timothy Dwight College and Gray Memorial Fund, 1960 November 5-1971 February 25 (Box 23, Folder 437)
      - Faculty Inquiries of Southeast Asia Studies Program
        - 1951-1954 (Box 23, Folder 438)
        - 1955-1957 (Box 23, Folder 439)
        - 1958-1959 (Box 23, Folder 440)
        - 1960-1962 (Box 23, Folder 441)
        - 1963-1964 (Box 23, Folder 442)
        - 1965-1970 (Box 23, Folder 443)
      - Yale University Graduate School correspondence, 1962-1970 (Box 23, Folder 444)
      - Yale University History Department, European History Search Committee committee, 1967-1968, undated (Box 23, Folder 445)
      - Administrative correspondence
        - A-C, 1966-1969 (Box 23, Folder 446)
        - D-G, 1966-1969 (Box 23, Folder 447)
        - H-L, 1966-1969 (Box 23, Folder 448)
        - M-P, 1966-1969 (Box 24, Folder 449)
        - Q-S, 1966-1969 (Box 24, Folder 450)
        - T-Z, 1966-1969 (Box 24, Folder 451)
      - Yale Alumni Seminar, 1963 December 23-1964 June 17, undated (Box 24, Folder 452)
      - Buddhist Studies, Proposed Center for Buddhist Studies in U.S.
        - correspondence, 1955-1957 August (Box 24, Folder 453)
        - correspondence, 1957 October-1960, undated (Box 24, Folder 454)
      - Yale Colloquium on Buddhist Studies, 1961 (Box 24, Folder 455)
      - Yale University Concilium on International Studies
        - correspondence, 1961 (Box 24, Folder 456)
        - correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 24, Folder 457)
        - correspondence, 1964-1965, undated (Box 24, Folder 458)
        - correspondence, 1966-1971 (Box 24, Folder 459)
      - Council on Comparative and European Studies
        - correspondence, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 460)
      - Council on International Relations
        - correspondence, 1963-1965 (Box 24, Folder 461)
      - Council on Southeast Asia Studies